Hey, buddy.
Yeah.
Hey, how's it going?
Good.
I really like that trick with the AI
logging. That's that's pretty neat.
I I've been doing similar stuff where in
some of my repos I'm I'm having it do
like it's almost like you're programming
with with language, right? You know,
and having it,
having it repeated over and over again.
Right.
Alright.
It's pretty clever.
Yeah, yeah. I mean,
you really start to think, you know,
just to use an old cliche outside the box
or you can do,
you do things that that you wouldn't want
and never have time to do.
Or the patience to do in the past,
you can ask AI to do it and get something,
you know, really useful really quickly.
So it's really,
it's really a game changer in that way in
my mind.
So two questions came up this this
morning and I forgot the first one.
Um.
So I'm trying to go through the deck and
remember what it was.
OK.
All right. Any questions?
It occurred to you while on your own way.
All right, well, I got something to share.
So let me do that.
So of course I asked AI about those
organization.
Instruction files and I put a file in the
the repo with the information that I gave
me and it's.
Basically saying, yeah,
the business and enterprise both have
this idea of a organizational instruction
plan.
I'm not exactly sure how you would create
one because I don't have access to. Sorry,
Boris.
No, no, sorry, something internal.
Oh, OK, all right. So anyway,
so you in addition to personalized
instructions and repository structures,
you have organizational instructions,
but you also something I didn't realize
that you could do,
which is something that is called a path
scoped instruction file.
And but going back to the and I'll talk
about that in a second, but the.
The organizational instruction file
basically ensures consistent behavior
across the organ.
So you you can basically in the I'm
assuming through the admin interface to
find what those the the contents of what
those files contain.
And they're basically, you know,
the contents is essentially the same
thing that you would put into a
repository.
A file,
but it gets utilized across the
organization.
Then the what I didn't I didn't know
about was these path based and.
There we go.
And basically these are the ability to
define instruction files at the at a path
level.
So in our instance we could we have here
a.
A calculator web application.
We have a calculator console application
and we have a.
Under the calculator web we have both a a
web calculator and.
Well, we haven't created this yet,
but we had a we we have.
We could have basically multiple
different kinds of technologies that we
have subfolders for under a project and
you can put a an instruction file in each
folder that applies just to that folder
and its subfolders.
So this allows you to do things
essentially like say OK,
this is this project is you know AC sharp
project that uses asp.
net and you can put an instruction file
in there that contains just instructions
that should be used for that particular
folder.
In a larger project,
so that's pretty nice.
I've got a couple of things I'd like to
experiment with them,
particularly with the idea that we talked
about earlier about using a sub repo to
store a a common instruction files.
And then can I create a copilot zone
instruction file at a folder level and
have it re reference specific
instructions that should be used within
that within that particular folder and
not have to duplicate them in multiple
folders that support the same technology
stack for instance?
All right.
Any comments or questions on that?
It we we don't need the enterprise one
for that, right? That's just any anything.
You do do. Yeah. Well,
for the for the for the folder-based ones,
no, you don't need that.
OK, now somebody had asked a question.
I'm sorry,
I've forgotten the question and the
person who asked it.
So if you recall the question that I
didn't answer,
you could you please post post it into
the chat and I'll I'll get to it later.
All right,
so let's start the presentation.
So this exercise is all about generating
more project or application specific
instruction files.
So we talked about using meta prompts to
and we did this in the the last one of
the.
Last examples of using a meta prompt to
scale the the instruction file creation
and one of the main benefits of that is
that it gets our our our instruction
files will now have a a common structure,
a common format to them which makes it
easier for them to be maintained.
It can capture,
we can capture module specific rules in
in in code domain and architectural
constraints, things like that like that.
And what we want to try to do here is
prompt Copilot to create instruction
files for the standards and conventions
of the of the tech,
I mean of the tech stack.
And review those instructions.
So why don't we give a a give that a a
take.
We've got a a small project that we can
analyze with that those instructions.
So let's go ahead and see if we can
create a separate instruction files.
For those,
for those tech stacks and I and I'll walk
through this as well because I can show
you a couple of interesting things about
how to accomplish that.
So you might want to try to follow along.
All right, so.
So the first thing I want to do is um.
Is make an inventory of what the?
Of what the tech stack actually is,
so I'll do a prompt.
Like, uh uh, grade an inventory.
So the technologies used in the projects.
Yeah.
And uh, this will go in inventory. Uh,
all of the.
The the files in the project and try to
come up with a an inventory of what's
actually involved in the project itself
and it'll hopefully it'll be a
comprehensive list and we can use that
list then to.
To actually generate instruction files
that are technology specific.
So um.
Yes.
So while that's running,
so so the the basic idea,
what I want to show after this is how we
can use sessions to actually execute
multiple prompts at the same time.
All right.
There was one prompt as finishing up that
I was.
I was basically following the same path
that you guys were following.
So I wanted to do as a part of the part
of the repo.
So I created that but still working on
the.
Inventory. All right,
so here comes our technology inventory.
Let me go ahead and push the instruction
files and the prompt files from the
previous exercises.
Kee them distinct from what we're doing
here.
All right, so.
So here's the technology inventory.
We can see here our core framework is dot
NET 9 with C# 11 plus.
We have a web framework which is consists
of a Razor pages and Kestrel you can.
Create architectural patterns here for
dependency injection and service layers.
UR framework UI framework which is
Bootstrap and Bootstrap JavaScript.
Some JavaScript libraries that are being
used, some classic asp.net static assets.
Our test framework using X unit
infrastructure for testing for Ms.
test and coverlets package management
with these new Nugget and and then we
have two different product,
two different three different project
types, one for.
The console application,
the web application and the test project.
And so this will be.
Providence.
Are we showing up?
So let's go ahead and create some
instruction files for these.
We can start off by looking at, you know,
just the core framework pieces and what
we can do is capture these and go down to.
Create a new chat session and then say I
want to have that chat session run in the
background and this essentially allows me
to delegate to a a background task the
the execution of this particular prompt.
And I can say great instruction file.
or
Uh, containing.
Standards.
And ractices.
Mm.
He needs technologies.
And if we submit that prompt.
It wants us to commit these changes first,
so let's go ahead and do that.
Stage them and then connect them.
All right.
So let me cancel out and we can put that
back in as another prompt. All right,
so it's got that.
And if we use this tab little icon over
here,
we can show the agent sessions and then
we can see here that we have a current
word process in progress session underway.
We can say I want to create a new session.
Hey John,
the refresh is kind of slow on my screen.
Um, yeah.
Can you point out what icon you clicked
again to navigate to?
Oh, sure, sure. It's a it's right here.
OK. Thank you.
Yeah.
And there's that.
So it's go ahead and running that prompt,
it looks like.
Um, it's finished with that, so we can.
Oh no, it's still in progress.
So let's go ahead and create a new
session and then we can go ahead and.
I changed to a different.
Uh, technology.
Well, it looks like I lost my inventory.
I thought that was in a new session.
What's the difference between a new
session and a new chat window?
Well,
the new chat just clears the context
And.
within the current session and the new
session is basically allows you to run
this as a background task.
So new session.
How can we see the old chats?
If I'm adding new chats, I can't.
I see the sessions,
but I don't see the previous chats.
Well,
you know these are the you can see here.
Here's the one about the project
technology. So I found that one.
Here's our the chat I I used to create
the Evergreen instructions.
Yeah.
That.
You can and you can see what the history
was of of that particular session.
So I'm still looking for a new session
here. If I go to the project technologies,
I can then take the security features.
It's going to be the.
The web framework for instance.
Then we can then say in that new session.
For these technologies.
And it should do it. There we go.
So now we see here this is for the core,
this is for the standards and practices
for the web application framework.
We can then go back to our project
technologies and select.
What's next? The architecture patterns?
By the new.
So when I added,
when I asked it to create an inventory of
the technologies used,
it just made a technology inventory MD
file and it's pretty bare bones.
It's not going into all the details like
you like it did for you there.
Good.
Hmm.
What what model are you using?
Uh, it's a good question. Says auto.
Yeah. So one could. Oh, go ahead.
I I guess.
Sorry, I got the same thing with GPT 4/1.
Well, I could try.
I see you're using Cloud Sonnet,
Yeah, try with a different model,
you know.
so I can try it with with that when we
change. When we change model,
should we create a new chat window or
session?
You don't have to.
But is it good to do it?
Yeah, I think, well, I mean,
it'll clear the context.
So that's always a good thing, right?
All right, so we're still in the process.
Now here we see an icon.
What this is telling us is that it wants
to ask us a question.
So here what's what it wants to do is
create a new item.
And it was it wants.
Alright.
So allow it to do those create those
folder and files.
All right.
And so we can see here that one of them
is not longer in progress, so.
When you're taking a look at this,
we can see that it changed one file.
And if we open that up,
we can see what file it changed also up
here.
There are.
It echoes what we see here in terms of
the number of sessions in progress as
well as the number of sessions that have
been run that we actually haven't clicked
on to look at.
So here we have create an instruction
file to move.
And these are different ones I was was
doing offline.
So this is basically how you manage
sessions and how you work with different
sessions.
We talked about looking at the the
session here which and the.
One file that was changed.
We can open up that file and see what the
contents of that file would be.
And we see the instruction that created
the the prompt that created that
instruction file. Now you know,
going back to what we talked about
beforehand,
we would probably want to create a prompt
file that creates this instruction file,
but you know.
Just for expediency purposes,
we see here this is all a.
net standards and practices.
What the core technologies are framework
versions, roject settings?
Um, what to do about console ASC core?
Roerty groups.
Implicit usings.
So all of that looks pretty good.
And then if you iterate it,
if you like that, you can apply it.
and it will become a part of the
Instructions and we also have one here
created for Kestrel and the and the razor
pages. So we have you know both.
I'm not sure about this message but.
Seems like I get it.
I've been getting it quite a bit during
this working with sessions and background
tasks.
So now we have those two,
we can go back to our session dialogue
and see if any of these are still in
progress.
And it's on CS that's still working on
creating a file.
And it here it's actually writing out a a
a new DI service layer instruction file.
Let's go ahead and keep this one as well.
So.
So I'm a little bit lost because like
when I did the summary it did very basic
information and so like how are you
making all these extra files now?
Are you just kind of because you had so
much more information than you just said
you just said oh you pulled that and you
said now make a separate file for each of
Right.
them or put it in in each folder like I'm
a little bit lost like what?
Alright, alright,
so let's backtrack a bit.
But.
So I I I created this project
technologies.
It's like like it's trying to do
something else,
but the prop that I used was.
You said create an inventory of the
technology used in this project,
Right. It's right up here.
Create an inventory of the technologies
I believe, right?
used in this project and it created this
list. And what you're saying,
does it not list any of the technologies?
Uh, very basic.
I mean I can show you or I can copy paste
it, but um.
If you want to show me, go ahead.
Not very.
Yeah,
I just put a screenshot in in in the chat.
They didn't talk about any kind of
architectural patterns.
They didn't talk about the web framework,
didn't talk about UI framework.
It's just very basic.
Well,
this is part of the non-deterministic
nature of it. So we if you wanted them,
if you if you wanted,
Yeah.
this might be a good reason to go to a to
create a prompt file first to make sure
that it's more complete,
but obviously if you added to the prompt
that you wanted to see also the.
Architectural or the architecture
patterns that are involved,
it would do that,
but it you know it has the the
programming languages, the frameworks,
so all that looks like it's pretty
correct. What I don't see here is.
Well,
I also see that you have the the previous
TypeScript,
Python and C# projects in there,
so that could be confusing it.
If you did a a a a pull of the repo,
I deleted those projects,
so I'm that's one significant difference
that.
Might be a factor in this in that I don't
have those those folders anymore in the
in this in this branch.
OK.
Yeah, I'll I'll pull the latest ones,
but I I didn't quite get the answer to my
question.
Like what's the difference between a new
chat window and a new session?
Is it is it basically the same thing or
is it or is that?
No, it's not quite.
It's not quite the same thing.
You know that you can clear your,
clear your your chat within within a
single session, but they're very close.
I mean, you know you can see here that.
You know, there's a lot of sessions.
That have been that have been created
going back last week and what you can do
if you did is that you can choose to
archive these sessions.
which will put them into a folder at the
very end with just the archived ones.
Up.
But we could, you know, we could,
we could ask the chat, right?
So we could say.
Yeah,
I asked about the difference between a
chat window and a session.
It said session is not is is outdated or
something.
I think it picked up something from one
of the instruction files.
Oh, right, right.
So one of the things I do for that is um.
I you know I'll have like another another
chat window available to you.
I have a a copilot window that I use
that's not connected any to the repo that
I can ask more generic questions with
like that.
That's how I got the information about
the.
Organizational.
The organizational pieces if I I can show
you what I was doing there.
Yeah,
so this is basically I can ask to prompt
here.
Good and get and get a response back so
we could do that.
Do that.
New conversation here and saying what is,
you know, the difference?
in between the noon.
No, get on. Okay.
Russian.
Chats.
Same chat mode, same instruction files,
same repo,
same model settings where a a session
resets the model's short term memory.
OK.
So it's it's more like a a.
More of a bigger it's like rebooting the
assistant as opposed to just clearing the
chat window.
that help?
Yeah, that helps.
OK,
so I I did pull the latest and I made a
new session and it did give a lot more
detail.
So from there you were then creating like
coding standards for.net. I mean what?
Yeah,
so then I what I did next is I I looked
at the this is not what I wanted.
Let's go to the top.
Looks like the other two have finished
while we were talking and I here at for
the project technology,
so I can go back to that session.
And what I did was basically selected a
piece of it like the core framework.
I created a new session which gives me a
new window and in that new session I said
you know, create the.
Instruction cloud, right?
And then spaced that in and then I
started a new session. In fact,
if we went back here,
I can do with another one as well that we
haven't done yet,
so might as well do it now.
So we did the architecture patterns.
Did we do the UI one standards web
framework? No, we didn't.
So let's do the UI framework.
So we'll copy that.
We'll go back to our local session.
OK.
And um.
OK. Thanks. I think I'm on track now.
Alright,
so we go ahead and submit that and it
will create a new session and here we can
go back and look at what it did for the
architecture guidelines.
Um.
So I created the this is the highlights.
So let's go ahead and look at the files
that I changed. So like there is the.
Let this one do the cradle file here.
O Here's the architectural patterns.
And the conversation associated with it.
So we can look at this.
And see the contents of that file.
Talks about the DI overview
characteristics use cases for most
services.
Signalton depending upon the scope of
service,
giving us a a warning what's not to do.
It's sort of lifetime decision 3.
And some code examples of how it actually
should be implemented.
Some best practices,
so I think that all of that is looking
pretty good.
And we can then say go ahead and.
Do I keep those changes?
And we'll keep calling them.
And now we have some new instruction
files that we can.
Then we can come in.
Notice in our little icon here that we're
consuming a good part of our our our
context window.
And that our system instructions are
starting to grow as we add more and more
things to our context.
All right. So any question,
I'd like to find out what that is.
Any questions on what we've done here?
John,
can I request that you add the prompts
that you're typing into the chat?
It would be helpful for me because I'm
Hello.
I'm usually like a step behind as I'm
trying to follow what to do and then I
Sure, sure.
miss the next one that you put in.
Right.
And then actually I put them all when I
was going through the baked version.
I put them all in the.
In the in the speaker's notes of the
slide presentation, so let me back up.
To the slides here.
And um.
Yeah, um.
I guess I can do it this way.
Just grab this guy and go to the chat.
Yeah, and if we're going too fast,
you know, feel free to slow me down.
So the MD file,
like how do you open it up into a nicer
viewer?
OK, that's a good question.
Let's see where I have that.
Yes.
Well, let's see that's.
I can probably get it from here control
shift.
I think it's those buttons right above
John,
OK.
where the play button and the split
window button. I think it's helpful. Yeah,
Up here.
right there.
I think it's the split window.
To the right of that.
Oh,
I think you can take those ellipses and
say show preview.
At least that's what I'm doing.
Well, yeah, there's two, you know,
this is what. So one,
this is what I was doing up until today
is you can say I want to open a preview.
Yeah.
That gives you the preview and then I
want to move that in or copy that into a
So.
new window and that gives you this right?
And I like this for the class because
Hmm.
it's much easier to see than in a small
window inside of a Visual Studio code.
But what I did is I created a key bind
and it does both.
I wanted to show you that,
so I wanted to go to here and say.
Um.
Open. Keep binding shortcuts. Jason.
That's the guy.
I'll paste this into chat.
And so if you open up your key bindings
and you add this,
then you if you do a control shift alt X
which is the keystroke that I've assigned
it to, it will do both of those commands.
So but you need to have an extension
called the multi-command extension
installed.
For it to work,
but once you have that that installed
then it will do a sequence of events
instead of just one and which is one is
the markdown show preview the slide and
the other one is the action to copy the
editor into a new window and it has a a
clause on it here that says the language.
In the in the editor must be a a marked
down component file,
which is what gets recognized as the
language.
I took a little bit to figure out,
but it works.
Sorry.
Alright, so that's what I've been doing.
OK,
so I see it also updates the read me file
and so the read me file is actually
pointing to this new instruction file.
So that's how like copilot knows that.
No,
no that that readme file is a part of the
architecture,
the the AI instructions that I showed you
earlier and the AI assisted output
instructions we look for reading.
Reading.
Require updating the top level read me
with a brief.
Entry whenever this process generates a
new file, where it is, what it is,
where it is at a one line prompt.
That's where that's coming from.
OK,
and how does this file get into the scope?
Is this? Is this a?
Well,
let's be it's in the GitHub dot GitHub
folder in the instructions folder and has
a instructions dot MD suffix.
Mhm.
Right.
So because of that then then it knows
that bring that into the context or how
No.
Yeah, yes.
Basically these instruction files are
how does that?
included with every prompt that gets
submitted and you could look at that if
we want to the diagnostics piece here and
look at.
You can then see what's actually
instructions are being included.
You can see here's the AI assisted output
instructions,
the architecture patterns for DI service
layer, the bootstrap instructions.
All of these are now a part of our
context.
The profiles, et cetera.
So one of the issues that comes up that
we that we'll talk about a little bit
later is.
What if I don't need all of those
contacts in my every single prompt?
I I only want it to focus on certain,
you know, certain things at certain times.
And that's where agents get into the the
mix and we can actually define an agent
that specifically reference to this
particular instruction files that are.
Relevant for the work that it's trying to
do,
and that way you can reduce the the the
size and the context,
the the consumption of the the context
window by by further being specific about
what is what's going on when you're
actually performing a particular task.
Right. OK. Yeah, 'cause I was,
I was concerned about that,
that all this stuff that's gonna be added
to the context and and that that not
And it is.
everything is needed all the time.
That's correct. That's correct.
And there's things that we're not taking
advantage of here that we're not using
for prompt files. For instance,
you can say that this particular prompt
file only applies to certain certain
files.
There's an applies to a clause that we
can use that that we're not using at this
point.
So there's other ways that we can fine
tune that context in in order for us to
to to manage it better.
And it's these skills I think that are
really critical for.
For really managing the the context
window and getting good good results out.
All right,
so we've got some new instruction files
created. Now,
one of the things that I wanted to do,
let's see is let me see if I can show you
this. Where is it?
It's a prompt, so it's a prompt file. OK,
I added this prompt into the project and
it's been committed,
so you should have this already if you do
a poll.
And with this is a pretty it's an
interesting prompt that I like in that.
We want our, you know,
we're bringing in all of this context
from all these different sources,
from all these different prompts.
Who is to say that there are that they
work well together and this, this,
this is a prompt that tries to identify
issues.
With those within all of the the context
that we've seen loaded already.
So what it basically does is it does an
analysis of the of what's currently in
the context and it looks for conflicting
instructions.
It looks for in factual inconsistencies,
contradictions.
Scope and priority conflicts,
technical incompatibilities,
communication gaps,
duplication redundancies,
and it and it spits out a category,
a description, where it is,
where it found it and what the impact
would be and a recommendation for.
Um, resolving it. So if we, uh,
clear our context window.
And run this. Uh.
We can say, uh, go ahead and submit.
Hello.
Check context prompt.
And this will do that analysis for us.
And again, this is this, you know,
in my view,
this is a really sophisticated analysis,
assuming that it's accurate, that it,
you know,
to manually go out and and conform all of
these, this analysis on our own.
It's quite a bit of effort and within a
matter of a couple of minutes we can get
back a a report that will point out areas
within the these,
all of these instruction files that we've
created.
That that might have some issues that we
want want to resolve.
So this is something that I do on a
fairly regular basis.
So every time I'm modifying my my
instruction files and the like I I want
to,
I want to run this to make sure that
there's.
There's none of these issues because if
any of these things get into the into the
context window,
it's going to confuse the A I and it's
going to, you know,
cause it to produce output that's
inconsistent or unreliable.
So having a a clean set of instruction
files.
Is is is important.
Any comments on on that?
Any questions on what we're trying to
accomplish here?
You're done. Oh, damn. I'm sorry.
Uh, no, I just gave a thumbs up.
I I didn't.
OK.
Yeah, it looks good.
Mm.
Oh, it's Stephen. Stephen.
Which is it?
E Steven. Yeah,
sorry I was kind of experimenting and
All right.
OK.
kind of looked away for a second.
And what exactly did you do here that's
thinking on you just type submit the
hashtag file check contacts prompt dot MD
Yeah, submit the, you know,
use the hashtag to select the file out of
or?
the open editor windows and I just ran
that and then it basically figured out
from there that I wanted to run this
prompt and so it's going through and
creating this in a.
Context analysis report right now.
So it's almost finished with it,
but that's what I that's what I did and
this is the.
The file that that contains the prompt
itself.
And while we're here,
Looks like we got the file created,
so let me look at it first and then I
wanted to show you something else about
the AI output instructions that might be.
But that should be of interest. All right,
so analysis complete 2 critical
literature images of the unresolved git
merge commit in the instruction file
instruction blocks.
And if we click on this,
it will take us and show us that I I
messed up a merge here and I've got
something committed that's not correct.
That's a good catch.
Model specific contradictions.
There's a contradiction between the
profile requirements and the template
example.
That would be something to look at some
high priority issues which are
inconsistent operator fields,
some medium priority issues.
So you can see that we've been building
out these these instruction files,
but we haven't actually done we've
introduced some things into that that we
would probably want to resolve.
So we can open up this context analysis
document that was created.
And you can see what the overall
assessment is, what the critical issue is,
a description. You can see here the code.
You can see what the impact will be.
So it cannot, you know,
be parsed as valid in YAML.
We didn't resolve the conflict by
determining which on resolving that.
That merge conflict, Martin,
here's one here that was talking about
the profile instructions versus the
instruction profile, the instruction file,
the two, the two meta.
Instruction files provide contradictory
guidance on a model specification,
and its recommendation is to update the
template in the instruction file.
Instruction files instruction to be
explicit on terms of the format.
And what we can do with these is that we
can we can say you know for for issue #2
in the preview context analysis support
MD.
Implement the recommendation.
And it will then read this file,
find the recommendation and then make the
appropriate modification to the file to
address the issue.
All right. Any questions on this?
So did you tell it to make a a file like
a cause like mine when I did it,
it just spit it out in the chat window.
It didn't make a separate file.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's those are the kinds of differences
Separate file.
that we see. It's got, you know,
I didn't instruct it to do it.
It inferred that I wanted a file maybe by
on previous activities.
I do find that copilot can remember
things beyond the.
Text window or the things that we tell it
and.
I'll give you a for instance I was
working.
And I was having it do um.
Basically run run a test and and and make
a modification and run a test and it and
then I would immediately do a a commit
afterwards and.
After doing it two or three times,
it started to automatically do the commit
after the prompt on its own without me
telling it.
So those are things that you'll see
happen that you you may not be able you
didn't explicitly instructed to do it and.
And it will,
it will infer that and and and do that
for you.
So let me go to the thing I was
interested in showing you about the.
8.
The instruction file for AI output
instructions. So let me open this up.
Uh.
You know in Windows so we can see the
whole thing and.
So what I was looking for here.
For example, authors much attach.
Or embed the following metadata at the
top of the artifact,
including the the metadata placement
policy and.
The thing that I I noticed about this is
that I can let me show you in a prompt.
Let me bring up the chat again. Oh,
we're in a different window. Oh,
we can do it here.
And then say, uh,
let's close everything but this guy.
Yeah, let's go ahead and take those.
Get that. All right, so.
Um.
Oh, this is a diagnostic window.
We don't need to save that,
so that's good. All right,
so context analysis report.
We can keep that as we'll want to try to
address that at some point.
Don't need our key bindings file.
I don't want to see the report anymore.
Let's keep our conversation and our
summary. Two things to accept here.
And we want the output instructions and
let's close.
All the others and new a new prompts and
chat and what I want to do here is is say.
Something like um.
What happens?
No, no, no, no, no.
Thanks.
PR.
And let me search for one of the class
here.
So this says submitting a pull request
containing modification to AI assisted
outputs.
The.
Before submitting A pull request,
you've got to validate that the chat log
was there,
that the the chat summary is there,
that the artifact metadata is there,
that the readme is updated,
the orphan orphan artifacts,
metadata format is correct, etcetera,
right? So what happens?
When a human creates a PR.
So can you point the enforcement only
triggers for files that are marked as a I
generated.
So what it's doing here is is changing
the.
It's proposing that we change that these
instruction files only something that
these instructions only apply to AI
generated content by by looking to see if
the the A I generated field is set to set
to true.
Right.
The effect of this would have been that
no human could actually submit a PR.
Unless the all of these criteria had been
met and that is not necessarily our our
intent is to have all of these artifacts
be part of the PR in order for it to be
accepted and as as a purchase as a pull
request.
Does that make sense?
So it's we we needed to be able to modify
the enforcement of this so that it only
only applies that when we want to when
we're actually doing.
When we're when we're actually doing uh
AI generated content and so we could say
um.
Go ahead and apply these changes.
And then it should go through and modify
the file.
It's misinterpreted what I've asked you
to do.
It thinks I need to apply these to AI
generated content,
so let me stop what it's doing.
It thinks it wants to make a modification
or evaluate this.
What I wanted to do instead is to update.
Mhm.
Hey guys, this instruction file.
So that.
It only applies.
Yeah.
Yeah, I in a little bit.
And let me try that in the chat.
And then you can see here that it's now
made some updates to that file.
To add the idea that it only checks for
AI generating complaints.
Now there's another issue with this file
that.
Um, I wanted to point out.
Oh, it's still thinking, sorry.
And if I Scroll down here in the file
when it gets to the.
Um.
The the enforcement of this policy what
we're which is saying that it wants to
prevent a PR from.
Being created that doesn't meet these
conditions.
Let's get to the part where it actually
tries to enforce that.
Where is it?
Yeah, it's fine. Yeah, here we go.
So let me open this up. We can see it.
Oops, gotta be in here.
And.
So for the Providence enforcement,
it says here's a GitHub action that we
that we can use to enforce the these
policies, right?
And you can see here that it it goes
ahead and gets the contents of the repo.
And then it runs a a a pretty
sophisticated batch script to do some of
the some to verify that the that the log
files exist. It it verifies that the.
The A I was generated, et cetera.
And what I don't like about this is that
this is now separating the logic of what
the requirements are from the from the
instruction files and in embedding it as.
Dash code inside of a a GitHub action.
So what I would rather do here is this.
Let's go ahead and keep our changes.
Or what we've done here and say I want a
new chat and say a place.
The get home.
Action.
Implementation.
With one.
Yeah.
Call.
Um.
AI not.
So let them think about that.
So the idea is is I think pretty
interesting in that we want the GitHub
action to run when the when we when
that's the activity that will trigger the
the action.
But instead of hard coding this in bash,
I'd rather have it actually call and
execute a prompt and and that prompt
would execute on the back end in GitHub
and then from and it would be one of the
prompts that we would have in our project
cause it.
As we retrieve it and then we would need
to then have that prompt return
information in a format that the action
could take and do something interesting
with.
So let's see what it's what it's done
here.
So our product and validation isn't using
an AI prompt.
It still does the the fetch of the data.
But the validate it has a validation
prompt now that's that's been inserted.
This is not precisely what I was
expecting.
So an improvement would be to take this
validation prompt out of the GitHub
action and and and put it into a prompt
file and then call the prompt file.
So that way if we change the prompt we
can do this and.
Source control here and and make it a
part of the and have it automatically be
included in the GitHub action and then it
does an exit here.
With the you know the policy file,
the base reference fail on error in terms
of what it finds as a result of the
actually executing the prompt.
So this is a a technique that I've used
in.
In projects where I I want to be able to
recognize,
you know that somebody has submitted a
pull request,
but I want to make sure that that it
conforms to what I expected to conform to
and so this will effectively prevent a a
PR once we deployed this into.
It is GitHub.
All right. Any questions on this?
So we've made, I think,
2 substantial improvements to our AI
output instructions.
So this is a good place for us to.
Submit our changes.
Any.
Well, let me capture that perhaps.
So that that saved the prompt you use
right in one of those summary files or
conversation file that's that's recording
that what prompt you used to update that
file.
Um, yes.
Let's see, where is that?
It's still not looking for this.
I don't want to go back here. Sorry.
So here we go and then if we go down and
look at our.
The logs.
We have our conversation history.
So this is for the cradles bootstraps.
I'm not architectural patterns CI service.
One of the things I'm working on that I
know that is another problem with.
My my AI output file is that it's it
doesn't.
It's not handling updates effectively.
So I've I've added some instructions to
it, but I don't see those being applied.
So wants to run a PowerShell command.
It's gonna get the contents.
And it's looking for a match.
So it's still thinking about this.
Some questions on uh.
OK.
On how to run this from a.
How to run a prompt from inside of a a
GitHub action?
But that did that actually update the
GitHub action or that's just the just
And I'll I'll.
That's just the that's just the just the
and it's just the prompt.
updates?
We could we could tell GitHub to go ahead
and.
Implement the GitHub action.
I I need to. I'm gonna move on though.
I'll I'll I'll implement the action in
the project tonight and then I can
demonstrate it tomorrow.
OK.
Let's go back to our deck.
And start our presentation again.
Alright,
and so we created our instruction file.
We did our context related issue analysis
and found that it had some work.
So let's talk about documentation
generation and and code analysis.
Some of the things that we can do here is
do an automatic read me and documentation
updates.
This is, I think,
particularly useful in a.
A a a brownfield project which you can
basically say you know create me a a a
read me file that contains a developer or
a a concurrent or create a developer's
guide that for this particular project
and it will then go through and look at
the contents of the project and give you
essentially your guidance on.
How to build it, how to how to deploy it,
how to how to how to write tests
everything,
all the all the main things that a new
developer would want to know about a
project when we're coming in.
You can do architecture diagram
generation.
You can you can ask it to explain,
you know a code that's might be
convoluted or difficult to understand,
and then you can use it to identify a
technical hotspots. I've used it to.
To look for defects, you know,
just go scan and it'll if it sees
patterns in the code that it recognizes
like static issues, it will point,
it'll be able to point those out and then
we're gonna do some hands on practice
actually to examine our code base and.
And do the same.
So let's some some techniques here,
some capabilities.
Let's for example generate or update the
the readme files.
So that's a pretty simple prompt we can
do that gives us a.
Quite a bit of value for that.
So if we close all the files here,
we'll create a new chat and I'll just
start that out and say let's say with the
workspace.
Update the Um.
Read me.
Files with your current state.
Of the projects.
And so workspace will tell it to scan the
the entire code base.
And here was you can see that it's
producing.
You know references. It's reading.
It's basically reading the file,
reading the references that it has.
It's adding information on.
Building what the development workflow is,
how to contribute to the project.
What requirements are for pull requests?
You notice that you might consider this
somewhat gold plating is adding a lot of
information to this file that we didn't
explicitly ask for,
but as I was talking about earlier,
I find it's better to.
Let the A I infer what you want,
and then you can pare it down by either
modifying the prompts or just editing the
file to reduce to to eliminate the
content you don't think is that that
valuable.
So looks like it's.
Created quite a bit of.
Information here.
So we're going through test structures,
looking at what are it's establishing
targets for.
Test coverage and the like.
Here let's move into including developer
guides and deployment guidelines.
And some some troubleshooting guidance.
So here we might want a more specific
prompt or even create a a prompt file
that is specific about what we expect to
be contained within the.
Within the documentation, so it.
Looks like it's done with and we wanted
to create. We have.
That's it.
See when it's updated.
I don't see an update to a read me.
It's in a conversation.
What scene where it's asking me to do
anything?
Oh, here's that's the conversation one.
That's fine.
So one time I was trying to get the A I
to do something and it was it kept
producing code I didn't like for various
different reasons.
So I kept on doing it and and revising
the prompt and resubmitting it and
undoing it over and over again.
And then copilot came back and said, well,
I've noticed that you've been rejecting a
a lot of my changes,
so let me try a different approach.
So a little bit of.
Dissing me a little bit for my works,
my workflow.
All right,
so now it's actually going to write out
the.
Write out the read me file.
It was interesting then.
that it didn't didn't write it up,
but no harm.
Questions on on the document
documentation stuff so far.
All right.
So then let's go back to the slides and
let that think.
Another nice thing that I don't know if
we've seen demonstrated yet is that if
I'm in a different application and I
switch away from the Visual Studio window
to some and do something else that when a
chat finishes its work it will.
Put up a little piece of toast that will
take me back to the the window when it's
done, which is nice,
nice for multitasking.
So we talked about updating readme files.
So the other things that we can do is
that we can actually have it do a mod
module level documentation.
So we could probably go back and.
Create a new session to do that,
so we create a new session.
And say I want to, um,
let's open up actually piece of code that
we can work with.
So here's our calculator.
For the web, we have a um.
A program file here and we can then say
add.
Uh.
Oh oh, add documentation.
To this one.
Let me look at this is one that we wanted.
That we have already we triggered,
but we never back and looked at again our
parsing limit.
And if we open that,
we can see what changes it made.
So it looks like we have all these
changes now.
And our updating readme session is has
finished and it changed 3 files.
Three different readme files.
And looks like it put a lot of different
additional information into those into
the main readme file, took some out.
Um.
I'll do that later.
Take a look at the web calculator file.
And see the changes there.
You can see it it it beefed up our
documentation.
Quite a bit and um.
Yes,
and he created a brand new file here for
the.
The web calculator feature that has
application settings and other things
that it needs to do.
So let's go ahead and keep all of that.
Any questions on this documentation?
You can produce AIAI preferences if we
give an API and and usage samples for
that.
And in order to keep documentation
aligned with code changes,
you can either run a prompt like this on
a regular basis or you can actually
create a a documentation instruction file.
That will require that that the
documentation be updated with every PR or
something along those lines so that the
documentation is always updated and you
and you can really delegate to AI.
The responsibility for updating that
documentation as opposed to having to be
a a a a piece of toil that you have to
work on and and and focus your energy on.
Questions on the documentation updates.
So let's talk about.
So is is there a documentation
instruction file in the sweet bulb?
No, we don't have one in the repo,
but you know,
you've seen how we created one,
an instruction file.
So you can very easily say, oh no,
create a prompt that creates an
instructional file for standards.
And conventions for documentation and
then run that instruction file to create
the create the instruction file and put
it in public your project.
I haven't created one yet, but you know,
it's on my list of things to look at.
OK,
so was I prompted to create a prompt to
create an instruction file that includes
details on documentation and best
practices? Is that what you said?
Something like that?
Yeah, yeah, that would be, you know,
that would be something like that, right.
So you could then fine tune those
instructions to be consistent with
whatever patterns or expectations that
you have for the documentation that gets
generated and then you'll be,
you'll see that that.
That done.
The the AI will take care of doing that
update for you.
OK.
OK, so um.
Moving on then,
we talked about the documentation updates,
so.
So.
I want to talk about a I generate
generation.
This is also something that's nice if we
looked at our main read me file again.
Let's uh close all these.
And go down to our main reading file.
And let's go ahead and display it so we
can see it better.
Uh, one of the things that it did.
Somewhere in here is it had a a a
calculator, a diagram,
which it did a decent job with in asking,
but it's not quite not exactly right.
I think there might have been another one
in here somewhere.
So um, what was this? The web calculation?
So we could say something like update.
Um.
Read me file.
And it plays the.
Yes.
Uh.
The web type architecture diagram.
With.
Seam floor architecture.
One minute.
So a couple of things.
C4 is just a is it's basically a a a
standard set of architecture diagrams
that were that many projects can use.
So this basically allows me to with,
you know,
very easily specify a set of diagrams
that need to be created.
And then Mermaid is a markdown extension
for creating a diagram.
So we'll it'll replace this text with
with a with a block of Mermaid or several
blocks of Mermaid that will contain the
diagrams now.
Just as a caveat,
I I have good results getting the
diagrams created,
but usually it takes a couple of tries to
get it to render properly.
So I I so I what I do is is to render the
diagrams and then if I see any issues
with it I go back to the prompt and.
And and ask it to fix the issue that it
finds.
Usually there's problems with
understanding the the, the, the, the,
the syntax. There's, you know,
usually problems with the syntax of the
the murmurary diagram that need to be
addressed.
So let's see if we could put anything in
here yet.
So here we see a seek for context diagram.
You see that it's marked as a mermaid
block and so that that was what causes
the mermaid extension to Visual Studio
Code to recognize that this is a diagram
and then and it knows how to render this
diagram based on that.
There's a container diagram,
a component diagram,
and so let's go ahead and.
Preview this. Oops,
I need everything in this diagram to do
it and.
So which read me is this?
I don't see that cheesy diagram,
So.
the ASCII diagram in in the in the read
me. Is that something?
I don't. I haven't pushed that change yet,
so I think we're gonna lose it.
But here we can see here the component
diagram that describes.
Let me zoom in on this.
Um.
Architecture diagram. A container diagram.
So here it's showing us that we have the
the the web application and the web
browser and what their responsibilities
are, the system contexts.
Nothing too sophisticated because our
application right now is very very basic,
but the same same idea applies.
It will create these kinds of diagrams.
You can also do data flow diagrams or
most of most of the UML type of diagrams
can be created this way.
If and if you have specific diagram types
that that aren't supported,
you can even define your own diagram
types in Mermaid and and get those to to
to render.
And again,
just to capture the prompt for the chat.
Nice.
That's that questions on the architecture
diagrams.
All right, good for us. Let's move on.
So as I said,
you can do your dependency graphs,
data flow diagrams,
you can and deployment topologies.
You know this is you know it's.
It's a it's a really nice technology,
but you know you have to you have to look
at the diagrams I think pretty carefully
to make sure that that it's interpreting
them correctly and I and again I have
seen errors in the mermaid output that
causes rendering issues that you might
have to address as well.
Then for context,
for for code explanation,
you can basically explain unfamiliar code
that you that you that you're not
familiar with.
So this is helpful when you're working
with code bases that you're.
That you didn't correct and you want to
understand how they're how they're put
together.
You can map call chains and dependencies,
identify hidden hidden coupling,
translate code into human readable
narratives,
all the capabilities that you can do.
If we were to go into our code base and
look at one of our files.
I like to do this particularly with a
test code.
Oh, where's my ears file? All right,
let's take a look at.
What we have here for tests so so
evaluation tests and they invalid input
test.
What the the reason I'm I'm pointing this
towards evaluating test is that.
Is that I really want to focus on making
sure that I understand what the tests are
doing and so I can look for gaps in test
coverage and so you can do something here
like it's just, you know, quick explain.
Of that code base.
And it will look at that selected code
and then.
Yeah,
and so we we should then take a look at
that code and and give us a reasonable
explanation for what it's trying to do.
I have a question about the mermaid thing.
Is that a plugin you have?
Because it's showing it's showing like
the the text that you know it doesn't
actually render the mermaid.
Right, you need to install the mermaid.
Uh.
OK, there's there's extension for that.
Yeah, there's an extension.
I I I mentioned it in passing.
Oh.
Yeah, and I I.
I think that would commit.
Oh, sorry, I messed up.
Yeah,
and I believe it in GitHub it it they
support it automatically.
So if you're looking at your markdown
Um.
documents it it I I've had a few problems
with it,
but it for most of the diagrams actually
show up if you're just looking at your
GitHub.
Um repo.
So yeah.
So here it has a markdown preview for
mermaid.
And that's what I'm using here.
There's also looks like there's some.
Other plugins as well.
Another mermaid preview down here. Um,
you have lots of options for that.
So we were talking about explanation.
So what?
What did this tell us about that little
piece of code?
This is a parameterized test method that
validates error handling for invalid
calculator inputs.
Then it if you notice,
it goes through then first explains what
the attributes are.
So it's going to do a a detailed
explanation for each of the the lines of
code that it's it's encountering.
So here we see the the theory marks this
as a parameterized test.
And with two with two attributes,
which is the inline data,
we can see that it's basically saying
this theory's gonna do run the test two
times with two different parameters
passed into it.
Then set up creates a a data table
instance.
Which is what it's doing here.
And then it does as an assertion that
expects an exception of any type to be
thrown and executes the Lambda inside it
to verify the behaviour.
And then there is a Lambda block which
has an explicit check and a fall back
validation.
Validation and it tests for empty
expressions and it tests for invalid math
syntax.
Both cases throw an exception as an
expected for error handling and then it
has a documentation about the naming
convention. Like I said,
this is when when I'm generating tests in
particular,
but you can do this also for any.
Block of code that that you're interested
in examining is that you can ask the the
ally to explain it and then that becomes,
you know,
something that gives you an idea of what
it's trying to do and you can use that to
help validate.
The logic you can even come back and
further prompt this to to give it a
situation that it might not have not have
considered right.
We can also you know as far as test cases
are concerned, you could say go ahead and.
Then look at the workspace.
And look more gaps.
Test coverage.
And this will also take a look at what
the code base and the test that we have
and tell us if there's any gaps and here
you can see a found.
But.
Yeah.
What was the previous prompt you used?
Sure. Well, there was the update,
the readme file to that was the architect
Yeah, but no, no, the one after that.
Didn't you have you did something else to
that one you wanted.
do the unit test stuff, right?
Yeah, I said here.
Well, what I did was I went into the.
Into the chat window into the the code
itself.
I said control I to bring up this window
and you can get to that.
I think also through a right I selected
and do a right click.
There's an exlain option here.
All right,
well then I what I did is I I went up and
I see. OK.
selected the text and did the control I
and I just used the command for explained.
All right.
And.
I'll put this in the charts.
All right. So,
so we can see here it's actually broken
down our code coverage about 95% for the
calculator service current and our
targets, right. So we're pretty good here.
Well,
we got nothing for the the rest of these,
the rest of this and then we can then
start targeting this is to actually
implement additional coverage and we'll
see here is actually spit out some
additional recommended test
implementation plan and what it what it
would like us to implement.
And we could then incorporate that into
our project and we can also again do the
same thing that we were doing before,
which is, you know,
selecting a test and actually and
actually asking it to to explain that to
us so that we fully understand exactly
what the test is trying to do.
Because you know and if you you can and
you can use we'll see a bit of this in
the the greenfield part of the course
where we're asking it to implement things
in a test driven development method.
So the tests get created before the code
gets written.
All right,
so we got a lot of changes here.
I don't want to get this wait,
wait too far away from me.
So let me stage these changes.
And let's see if it comes up with a
decent prompt or commit message.
Updated the legacy calculator read me
file,
added a PowerShell script for replacing
sections and instruction files.
Probably can drop that.
More README file updates.
All right,
so you don't have all those changes in
the repo.
And let's push those changes, OK.
Back to the slides and then we can bounce
back here.
So we talked about explaining and
coupling.
And translating code.
This is kind of interesting in that.
You can you can select a piece of code
and say uh.
I'll click here the chat to see this and
then do you go back here and say.
And then we'll see what it does with that.
So we ask it to rewrite this piece of
code and tell us what it looks would look
like in Go.
All right. Any questions on some of this?
Had a question.
So this session was focused on a lot of
Yeah.
the instruction file creation for the
entire repository,
and this is for brownfield projects, so.
You know,
like typically there'd be like large code
bases, multiple projects,
multiple libraries, unit test projects.
Sure.
I'm trying to understand how to bridge
the gap between the initial setup.
Of all of these new instructions with
regards to standards, coding practices,
technologies and targeting down to the
smaller set,
which I think you were saying that was
the approach we should be taking for
large.
Legacy code bases, right?
You want to target small changes 1st and
then work your way up to larger
refactoring areas.
Sure.
So let's use this example of I have this
small project with a unit test project
applied to it. Some human wrote.
A large number of unit tests in there.
It's probably not complying to the
instruction files that you just asked it
to auto generate.
How do you bridge the gap between?
Working from the the top level of the
repo down to the targeted area to fix an
area of code, what would your approach be?
All right. All right.
So we're just talking about a particular
area, like a test project.
Yeah.
Then what I would do is I would include
in the prompt the the the name of the
project that I wanted it to to look at,
right?
So that way this was we we discussed this
earlier when we were talking about scoped.
How to scope a prompt and and restrict
what it's actually looking at.
So you can essentially look at this large
project as a whole solution as a whole
bunch of individual projects and you can
then target them one by one for
improvements in in by having it look at
just that one project or or even.
Single file in that project and then and
then suggest improvements for that
particular area or piece of the
application.
So you can drill down as deep as you want
into that and make it as precise as you
So.
need to be.
OK,
so am I hearing that you wouldn't create
the instruction files that you want to
achieve an Evergreen type of result from
M.
No, no, no.
I think you would create the instruction
first?
files because states certainly would
guide any new code that you write.
It would use those instruction files when
AI was creating them.
But we can also use those instruction
files on that existing code base because
we have some existing code in this test
file.
And we also have some existing code in
the the repo.
OK.
So let me bring up a a piece of code that
we can target here.
So we have our services for instance.
So I have a calculator service.
I can bring up just this one file.
For instance,
and I can create a new chat window and I
can say.
Say um review.
Yes.
Which is calculator service and this
could be a project or it could be some
other scoped area,
but we're scoping it down to this one
file and.
Report.
any differences.
Strong meeting.
Instruction files.
OK, I think I get it now.
And with that,
there was a look at this file.
It'll see if there's anything that is
about it,
about all the files that we've created,
and then it will create a list of them.
And.
One of the things that I do often with
this is I take your findings and create
GitHub issues for what you found, right?
And if you have the GitHub CLI installed
OK.
and you've allowed it to.
Create issues in the repo,
then it will go ahead and just actually
push them into into the repository and
actually you can see examples of that in
the repository already when I I ran this
against the the baked version of this
code base and asked.
To to create issues for for things that
it found that were not Evergreen,
which we can do.
So it just found some minor things
basically, right?
Invalid expressions are considered to be
expected user error.
So we should treat them as a a a result
type failure rather than as exceptions,
right?
So that's I I think a good a good
observation, right? We shouldn't be,
you know, if you type in a letter,
you should you should be giving them a a
an error message,
an error message and not throwing an
exception. That's because that.
Doesn't get handled.
So if I,
instead of saying comply to the
instruction files,
said apply to the coding standard naming
convention,
let's say a small subset right on on the
Sure. Yep. Yep.
the file,
and then I also told AI now commit my
changes, what would happen in that case?
Would it actually commit the changes or
would it block me because it's not
complying to?
Like a greater standard of the
instructions.
Instructions are not applied unless you
tell it to.
Uh.
Well, yeah,
they they get the instructions get
triggered and the way in which the the,
you know,
the instruction files are created is that
they're targeted at a new new code that
gets created or you know, new files.
That we're creating. So if we were to.
Which is something like I said I was
working on in terms of some of the
instructions that I am trying to
understand,
you know how it treats updates to
existing files and how it, you know,
how it applies the instruction files when
it does that.
That's like a gap in my instruction files
that I'm I'm.
I'm closing right now,
but you know what I was saying earlier is
that we we know we have our instruction
file for where is it Evergreen
development here.
We can use that instruction file to look
at the whole code base and say that you
know, I'm sorry, looking at this file.
And then up the workspace.
Review code your compliance with
instructions.
Generate.
I get home.
So this is looking at the whole code base.
But.
But looking, you know,
looking for just things that are
violating the.
And it's the the the are the instructions
for our ever encoding instructions.
So here this is an example,
but we could easily I guess apply this
for individual files or individual
portions of the of the code base or or
whatever we like.
So who wants to know to create actual
GitHub issues,
generate A detailed compliance report,
or provide code templates for
implementing the missing quality gates?
So we could say do all three.
But let's go to and we'll just say we'll
go ahead and do one.
And so this will actually go through.
Create a descripcion.
acceptance criteria.
And we can switch over to GitHub.
Since I've already done this.
Projects.
Let's see that right now there's 13 that
was the ones I created earlier,
but you can see that it creates pretty
good issues.
Now another thing that you can do here
that's also useful not with this account.
I have one account that actually is a a
GitHub.
Pro plus account which is this one.
So looking at that same issue with the
pro account I can say assign this to
copilot and what that will do will
essentially on.
Copilot's back end, GitHub's back end.
You will attempt to implement the
recommendations here for that particular
issue.
So what it will do is it will go ahead
and assign it.
We can provide additional instructions it
will.
It will take it over.
It will create essentially a session of
its own for the implementation.
And we'll be able to.
Uh, let's see, you know here we see this.
Here is our work in progress for those
health checks.
And well,
thanks us for giving it the work.
Here's the issue that we assigned to it.
And create an initial plan.
I'm getting a piece of notification here
that says that the work is completed,
so we could then look at the.
Uh, commits.
Well,
it's just on the initial plan so far,
so it's updated the work item with the
plan.
And.
And then once it's finished,
it'll essentially assign us as reviewers
and we can then review the code that it's
created.
All right.
Any other questions or comments on this?
This this is another way of delegating,
but of course you're gonna need to get up
to do that.
Is there a specific prompt you use for
that one? Sorry, I was.
No,
all I did was go into actually GitHub
I didn't quite see that.
itself and with an account that has this
ability.
I just noticed here that it that the
assignee is to copilot.
And and I what I did is I was just
assigned copilot to that particular to
that issue and it then taken over from
there.
And you'll notice here it created a
branch called the Copilot Health Checks
I see.
Intermobility.
And then you can.
Uh,
take a look at what it work and it's done
there.
All right, technical debt.
So I've done it.
We got a little bit of this exploration
into the code base looking for.
You know,
looking for gaps in test coverage and and
the like.
You can also do things like look for out
outdated code.
This is what I think is interesting about
this is that we created these instruction
files.
These are a point in time reference to
what the standards and practices are.
And practices are at this time,
if a if things change or if there's new
technology available,
we can update our instruction file and
then we can ask AI to examine the code
base like a for deviations for the
instruction file and it will then point
out areas in the code base.
That need to be upgraded for that new
technology that might have come online or
for new patterns that you want to take
advantage of.
If you want to do a particular type or
change your architecture in some way,
you can.
Code that into your instruction files and
then compare the code base against it to
in order to find areas within the code
base that need to be addressed and then
you can do what I just did now and use it
to create issues in the in in a
repository.
And in fact,
I mean if you if you don't have the
integration to your to your issue
tracking system,
you can have it generate text files that
you can then use to paste into your issue
tracking system as well.
So there's many ways that you can
accomplish that. Look for duplicate logic.
Look like I said, look for dead logic,
look for missing tests,
which we did some of that.
Look for things that are a high complex
complexity.
You can look for things like tight
coupling.
So show me areas of the the application
where things are tightly coupled.
And you can actually look and look for
security problems and and and and create
security issues.
And I've I've done this on on a few code
bases and it it tends to produce good
output from that and and what you can do
with this is you can easily.
Create a fairly substantial backlog of
technical debt simply by asking AI to
look at the code base for specific kinds
of issues. Now these are fairly generic,
but if you're looking for particular
types of problems, you can find them.
In the code base and you having AI do the
the research for you.
All right, so here's an example practice.
I generated some code documents,
select a module or a file and ask AI to
generate a summary of that file,
what the key responsibilities are,
what the inputs and outputs are,
and any known risks.
You can then ask it to add Providence
metadata if it's not already there and
and then you can review that information.
So go ahead and give a shot at that and
this will probably be our last exercise
for the day.
Mhm.
But.
What would be the best file in this
project?
Like calculator service isn't that big.
Is there a better?
Well, there's, yeah,
I think they're all pretty small.
It's one of the things that we didn't get
to build up too much on it,
but that's a good file.
I think to start with documentation.
Also look at the the program dot CS file
has a little bit of code in it.
OK.
And you could also have it look at the
whole the whole code base too.
I have a thought at one point to just
have everybody go out and pick a GitHub
project that.
Needed some help.
And see if we could as our as our
brownfield example and see if we can
improve it.
So the ad providence metadata like what?
What prompt do you recommend for that?
Um.
Uh.
I would I would say add something like
add the AI generated metadata to this
file.
Mm.
So created a sidecar.
Uh, metadata file.
Interesting.
I was thinking of talking about how you
know this is C#,
should use XML for the generated comments
and this and that, but.
That's what it said to do.
Mm.
All right,
so I've been notified that the the
copilot is in or GitHub is making
progress on that issue.
It's doing a final test run now.
And in order to finish up this work,
if we look at the pull request itself.
4 commits and 19 files have been changed.
That it had health check endpoints,
structured logging,
application insights using open telemetry,
testing and and then tested and
validating and doing a coder unit
security stand and.
It's still working on that.
So how was this issue originally created?
Was this created from within the VS code
or did you create this?
Yes, we asked.
In one of the earlier prompts,
we asked it to create.
And.
So yeah, I was looking for some go.
Uh, update. So we had a a prompt earlier.
Oh, good, great.
Generate GitHub issues for your findings.
that
Right and so it it since it has the the
GitHub CLI installed it it can it knows
how to then use that CLI then to create
an issue.
If not you could just say create files
and it will create an an issue file.
That you know has the same content and
you could use that to cut and paste into
whatever tool that you use for tracking
tracking issues.
But if there's a MCP server for that,
whatever tool you're using,
you could actually.
Invoke that tool and have it actually do
the work for you.
Are we gonna cover MCP tools in this
class? OK.
Yeah, yeah, we will.
So what for the A I generated metadata on
on AC sharp file?
Is it just at the very top in do we use
like summary text or is it just just
comments? You know, code comments?
We.
Well, you could, you could specifically,
you know, call out that you wanted to,
you know, you want the the C#, you know.
Documentation to be added to the file,
right? In fact,
if you just if you have AC shar file that
you're open and you add documentation to
it,
it's gonna automatically assume that's
what you want.
Right.
Mhm.
Um.
But yeah,
here it just used like basically XML at
OK.
the top of the file, you know,
just like comment like code comments.
Right, right, right. And everything.
So this goes back to, you know,
Excuse me, not not XML.
the requirements that we would have in
the A I assisted output instructions that
we might want to tweak those.
Specifically for a particular types of of
files so that we get what we what we
would like to more than what we would
like to see.
So if he didn't like the XML at the top
and you wanted to use AC sharp,
you know documentation standards.
You could do that.
Yeah,
so it's really up to us what we wanna do
with that. I mean,
it's pretty verbose at the top of the
Right. So yeah, so you know,
that's really, you know,
file, so.
that's where the instruction files really
help us because they allow us to tailor
the output to be exactly what we want it
to be.
And we just need to make sure that we
have those instructions.
Defined and we should be good to go from
there.
So I see that it's.
Using a different model in the shows in
in in Visual Studio,
I'm using Cloud Sonnet 4.5.
What it's putting in the I generated
metadata is Cloud 3.5 is it?
Yeah.
So that's that's what I was referring to
earlier when I was talking about this.
It's it's the work that I've done on this,
it's it's not possible to get the exact
model it it's.
From the, from the, from the A I itself.
And so it's inferring this from what the
latest model is right now.
So that's something.
That I'm still, you know,
trying to find a workaround for to see if
there's something that would work,
and I haven't found anything better than
OK.
what I see right now.
Any other questions?
All right, that's it for today.
Tomorrow we'll be finishing up our our
our brownfield work and then we'll move
into Greenfield.
So that'll and that'll be exciting as
well.
And I'll see you tomorrow.
Thanks, John.
Thank you, John.
Thanks.
Thank you.
You're welcome. See you tomorrow.
Thanks. Bye.